Hi Georgie, how are you I'm pretty good Thank you Phil how are you doing I'm really good I think you're gonna be even better when you find out what we're talking about today tell
Me Well I know we often talk about food but today we're talking about desserts You were right I love desserts or puddings
Sometimes we call them puddings in the UK I have a big sweet tooth so yeah I will love this I will love talking about.
's get started Well first, before we start talking about my favorite topic, we have to remind our listeners that they can find a free worksheet and transcript to help them learn atbblearningenglish.com. .
So Georgie, I think this is a silly question and I think I know the answer already but do you like desserts do I like desserts
I love desserts I have a really big sweet tooth which means that I really like sweet things.
Sugy things, I put sugar in my coffee sometimes, but I if I'm in a restaurant, I will always order a dessert, I would prefer to have a dessert or pudding than astarer actually.
Um yeah, what about you do you like themum Yeah, I do, I think I think in a restaurant I'd probably order a starter rather than a dessert,
But yeah, it's nice when you get a good one it's so good.
I quite like homemade desserts so I don't know homemade apple crumble oh that's really good, so that's when we cook the apples a little bit so they're quite soft and then we put.
A biscuit topping at the top and it's really, really delicious and it's a hot a hot dessert Yeah and a lot of fruit puddings that I quite like is they're sweet.
But they're also a bit sharp as well, a bit sweet a bit sour it's a really nice combination I love that well I do love fruit puddings but I am a chocolate
Person so if I have a menu, In a restaurant, I will always look for the chocolate dessert, maybe a chocolate brownie chocolate cake, ice cream as well, that's a really good dessert.
And sometimes if you're feeling very full after the meal.
Ice cream is a good option because it doesn't feel too filling, does it do you like ice cream Yes,
I really love ice cream I like most flavors of ice cream I think I like the creamy ones, And then some of the fruity ones as well like mango ice cream or something on a hot day,
Like you can't beat it Do you often eat dessert No, I don't think I do not that often I keep it as a treat for like,
Special occasion or something to make a meal feel really special dessert with it, but yeah I wouldn't I wouldn't have it every week, I don't think no because it's not very healthy to eat too much sugar is it?
You're very good I do eat pudding and dessert quite a lot I yeah, I just get really strong sugar cravings after meals what's the best dessert you've ever had?
Okay, well, I I said that my favorite puddings are chocolate tea, but actually I think the best dessert I've ever tried because it was the first Time.
Was when I was in Jordan and I tried something called a canaffa and this is like a it's actually a cheesy pudding so it has cheese in it but it then
Has a kind of crispy topping.
That I think is made of honey or sugary syrup, so it has the kind of savory, which means salty of the cheese, the salty flavor of the cheese plus the sugary bit at the top and it was,
So delicious I ate all of it and it's yeah very rich that sounds amazing do you have a favorite one the one I can remember best I had it in a restaurant
In Argentina about20 years ago.
And I can still remember it and it was deep fried ice cream, which sounds crazy, it's like ice cream and it was fried in like sweet batter or pastry.
It was amazing and I can remember it20 years later that sounds incredible that's something that's very common in Scotland actually I'm surprised you had it in Argentina maybe not ice cream but in Scotland
They like to deep fry so.
Put something in a lot of oil, they do that with chocolate bars and things like that so yeah, not very healthy, no, not at all, but lovely so delicious.
Okay so let's recap the vocabulary that we've been looking at today we're talking about desserts we also particularly in the UK call them puddings and that's just
Something sweet that you eat at the end of a meal Yes if you really like puddings and desserts and sweet things you could be described as having a sweet tooth I have a sweet tooth
For example Yes of course puddings aren't just sweet I talked about apple,
Cmble a very traditional British pudding and it's a little bit sharp which kind of means the same as sour,
So like a lemon pudding would be sharp or sour we also heard the word filling which describes a food or a pudding which makes you feel full
Oh and Georgie you said you were a chocolate person, What do you mean by that that just means that I am a person who really likes chocolate
What kind of person are you feel I think I might be an ice cream person I'm also an ice cream person I'm also a chocolate person.
Well Phil, that is the end of this episode of Real easyy English we will of course be back next week with another conversation Yes we will and don't forget.
That we have a worksheet that you can get from our website and that'sbblearningenglish.com. goodbye goodbye.